A Guide to the Lantern Slides from the University of Virginia, ca. 1920-1941
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Lantern Slides from the University of Virginia ca. 1920-1941
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
This collection consists of 173 glass lantern slides.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was an archival transfer from the Music Library, 2006.
Contents List
- Scores
  - Plainsong Organum Faux Bourdon
    L-1486
  - Notation- With Illumination Score
    L-1487
  - Brahms Arpeggio Themes
    L-1488
  - Score- Figured Bass Realized Corelli Sonata
    L-1489
  - Lute Tablature Score
    L-1490
  - Score- Schumann Symphony No. 1
    L-1491
  - Score- Figured Bass- Example Corelli Sonata
    L-1492
  - Score- Cadenza sung by Farinelli
    L-1493
  - Score- Cadenza- Vocal La Finta Caheriera, Source: DIF
    L-1494
  - Score- Scarlatti, a. Aria Tal Se Premo, Source: DENT
    L-1495
  - Mozart Don Giovanni Trio
    L-1496
  - Score- Cadenza- Vocal, Source: DENT
    L-1497
  - Score- Beethoven Mass
    L-1498
  - Beethoven Sketches for 9th Symphony (#2)
    L-1499
  - Beethoven Sketches for 9th Symphony (#1)
    L-1500
  - Score- Beethoven Symphony 9 Scherzo Showing Timpani Solo
    L-1501
  - Score- Berlioz Fantastic Symphony Showing Size of Orchestra
    L-1502
  - Sibelius Symphony No. 2
    L-1503
  - Berlioz Score- Page of Requiem
    L-1504
  - Sibelius Symphony No. 5
    L-1505
  - Straus- Themes from Don Juan and Don Quixote
    L-1506
  - Score- Jefferson and Liberty
    L-1507
  - Schuönberg Pierrot Lunaire
    L-1508
  - Stravinsky Rite of Spring
    L-1509
  - Score: Schönberg Piano Music
    L-1510
  - Casella Preludio
    L-1511
  - Score- Stravinsky- Rite of Spring- Final Dance
    L-1512
  - Section I: Doh chord with all its leaps and scale passages, Theory book.
    L-1513
  - Ibid. p. 2
    L-1514
  - Ibid. p. 3
    L-1515
  - Ibid. p. 4
    L-1516
  - Ibid. p.10
    L-1517
  - Ibid. p.12
    L-1518
- Charts
  - Arrangement- Seating Haydn Orchestra
    L-1519
  - Plan of Concerto Typical First Movement
    L-1520
  - Arrangement- Seating Beethoven Orchestra
    L-1521
  - Arrangement- Seating Wagnerian Orchestra
    L-1522
  - Plan of Typical Classical Symphony
    L-1523
  - Plan of Typical Concerto
    L-1524
  - Plan of Typical Classical Concerto
    L-1525
  - Arrangement- Seating (Strav.) Modern- Orchestra
    L-1526
  - Chart- Outline of History of Music Showing Peak of Styles
    L-1527
  - Plan of Typical Movement in Sonata Form
    L-1528
  - Map- North-East Europe Showing Extent of Burgundy
    L-1529
  - Opera- List of French Opera Composers 19th Century
    L-1530
  - Opera- 19th Century German Opera Composers
    L-1531
  - Opera- List of Italian Opera Composer 19th Century
    L-1532
- Instruments
  - Instruments- Viola Da Gamba
    L-1533
  - Instruments- Portative Organ 1570
    L-1534
  - Harpsichord which belonged to J.S. Bach
    L-1535
  - Clavichord
    L-1536
  - Instruments: Italian Clavichord, German Regal Italian Spinet and Portative
    L-1537
  - Dance at 'Sign Venus' and Instruments, 15th Century Dancer
    L-1538
  - Instruments Organ Positive
    L-1539
  - Instrument Organ, Medieval, Plate From Gafurius
    L-1540
  - Double-bass
    L-1541
  - Instruments- Viol Da Gamba (Portrait by Nattier)
    L-1542
  - Clarinet
    L-1543
  - Harpsichord Action
    L-1544
  - Viola
    L-1545
  - Violin
    L-1546
  - Violoncello
    L-1547
  - Oboe
    L-1548
  - Instrument- Medieval Instruments and Dancing, Line Drawing
    L-1549
  - Flute
    L-1550
  - Bassoon
    L-1551
  - Contra Bassoon
    L-1552
  - Piccolo
    L-1553
  - Bass Clarinet
    L-1554
  - French Horn
    L-1555
  - English Horn
    L-1556
  - Trumpet
    L-1557
  - Tuba
    L-1558
  - Trombone
    L-1559
  - Harp
    L-1560
  - Tympani
    L-1561
  - Mozart D. Major Symphony First Page Full Score
    L-1562
- Portraits
  - Brahms-Portrait
    L-1563
  - Beethoven
    L-1564
  - Chopin- Portrait
    L-1565
  - Berlioz- Portrait
    L-1566
  - Bull- Portrait
    L-1567
  - Schumann- Portrait
    L-1568
  - Wagner Aet. 29
    L-1569
  - Wagner Caricature
    L-1570
  - Liszt Portrait
    L-1571
  - Dufay and Binchois- Portraits
    L-1572
  - Des Pres Portrait
    L-1573
  - Palestrina- Portrait Presenting Mass to Pope
    L-1574
  - Portrait Handel Engraving from Portrait S. Hudson
    L-1575
  - A. Corelli
    L-1576
  - Sweelinck- Portrait
    L-1577
  - Portrait H. Purcell
    L-1578
  - Portrait W.F. Bach
    L-1579
  - Portrait C.P.E. Bach
    L-1580
  - F. J. Haydn (by Grove)
    L-1581
  - Gluck- Portrait
    L-1582
  - F. Couperin
    L-1583
  - Handel-Portrait by Hodson
    L-1584
  - Portrait G. Costeley
    L-1585
  - Rameau Portrait
    L-1586
  - Lulli Portrait
    L-1587
  - D. Scarlatti
    L-1588
  - Tallis Portrait
    L-1589
  - Portrait- MacDowell
    L-1590
  - Stravinsky- Portrai By Picasso
    L-1591
  - Portrait Okeghem and Choir
    L-1592
- Opera
  - Opera- Paris the Centre of the Opera in the 19th Century
    L-1593
  - Opera- Plan of Berkshire Opera Theatre Des[igned by] Saarinen 1941
    L-1594
  - Opera- Plan of Wagner's Festspielhaus (cross section)
    L-1595
  - Opera- Paris Opera House Cross Section {Architect: Casmier 1875]
    L-1596
  - Opera- Scene from Beggar's Opera
    L-1597
  - Opera- 1. Greek Space Stage 2. Modern Space Stage Bel Geddes 3. Peep Show Stage, 4. Modern Design = Space Stage and Peep Stage
    L-1598
  - Opera- Stage Setting by Bibiena for an Opera 18th century
    L-1599
  - Opera- Stage Setting by Burnacini for La Monarchia Latina Triofante by A. Draghi
    L-1600
  - Opera- Perspective Sets Peruzzi, Designer. Early 16th century
    L-1601
  - Opera- France (Raneau)
    L-1602
  - Stage Setting
    L-1603
  - Opera- Imperial Theatre in Vienna Burnacini, Architect c. 1668
    L-1604
  - Opera- Palladio Theatre at Vicenza 1585
    L-1605
  - Opera- Costume Baroque Costume
    L-1606
  - Opera- Roman Theatre At Ostia
    L-1607
  - Opera- Greek Theatre at Epidauros
    L-1608
  - Moazart- Magic Flute, 1794
  - Opera Stage Setting
    L-1609
  - Stage Sets- Cesti Pomo Doro, Act V
    L-1610
  - Opera- The Elements of Music Drama
    L-1611
  - Opera- Plan of Peep-show Stage
    L-1612
  - Opera Chart Historical Development of Music Drama
    L-1613
  - Opera Scaramuccia
    L-1614
  - Opera- Greek Theatre at Epidauros
    L-1615
  - Opera- Stage Set- Meistersanger Act I First Performance Munich 1868
    L-1616
  - Opera- Stage Set- Walkure. Design, J. Hoffmann. 1st Bayreuth Perf. 1876
    L-1617
  - Opera- Stage Set Walkure Design L. Sievert. c. 1926
    L-1618
  - Opera- Stage Set- Pelleas Design J. Urban, Metropolitan
    L-1619
  - Opera- Opera House at Bayreuth, designed by Galli-Bibiena, 1748
    L-1620
  - Opera- Plan of Concealed Orchestra- Bayreauth
    L-1621
- Miscellaneous
  - Jacques-Ange Gabriel, Bedroom of Louis XV Versaille
    L-1622
  - [George F. Handel] Pavilion erected in Green Park for Fire Works music
    L-1623
  - Fran[cesco] Borromini, Baroque, Rome, University Court and St. Ivo
    L-1624
  - Johann Michael Fischer, Kloster Kirche in Ottobeuren, Interior
    L-1625
  - J[acques-Louis] David, Schwoeren [?] Horatien Louvre 1785
    L-1626
  - [Jacques-Louis] David Mme, Recamier Detail Louvre 1800
    L-1627
  - [Jacques-Louis] David, French painting, Madame Recamier Louvre 1800
    L-1628
  - M[atthaus Daniel] Poeppelmann, Baroque, Dresden, Crown Tower of the Zwinger
    L-1629
  - Charlottenburg Palace, The Porcelain Room
    L-1630
  - [Alexandre Benois] Petrouchka. Tableau I
    L-1631
  - [Alexandre] Benois Petrouchka, Tableau I
    L-1632
  - [Alexandre Benois] Petrouchka, Tableau II
    L-1633
  - [Alexandre Benois] Petrouchka, Costumes: Coachman, Merchant, Nursemaid
    L-1634
  - [Alexandre Benois] Petrouchka, Costumes: Moor, Ballerina, Petrouchka
    L-1635
  - [Alexandre Benois] Petrouchka, Costume
    L-1636
  - [Alexandre] Benois Petrouchka, Charlatan Costume
    L-1637
  - Council Room, Fontainebleau, Wall paintings by [Francois] Boucher, [Jean-Baptiste] Van Loo, etc
    L-1638
  - [J. S. Bach] Eisenach, Bach's birthplace [Terry?]
    L-1639
  - [J. S. Bach] Leipzig, Thomaskirche Interior
    L-1640
  - [J. S. Bach] Leipzig, Thomaskirche & Schule
    L-1641
  - [J. S. Bach] Arnstadt, Bach's organ
    L-1642
  - [J. S. Bach] Arnstadt. Bonifacius Kirche: Interior
    L-1643
  - [J.S. Bach] Halle Liebfrauen Kirche
    L-1644
  - [Camille] Pissarro Avenue de l'Opera
    L-1645
  - [Jean Auguste Dominique] Ingres, Oedipus bef[ore?] Sphinx, 1808
    L-1646
  - [Jean Auguste Dominique] Ingres The Golden Age. C. 1855?
    L-1647
  - [Jean Auguste Dominique] Ingres [Apotheosis of Homer], 1827
    L-1648
  - [Eugene] Delacroix Portrait de [Frederic Chopin] Louvre, 1838
    L-1649
  - [Eugene] Delacroix, La liberte guidant le peuple Louvre, 1830
    L-1650
  - [Eugene] Delacroix Bark of Dante Louvre, 1822
    L-1651
  - Fernand Leger, Composition 1925 S, Guggenheim Collection
    L-1652
  - [Claude] Monet Gare St. Lazare
    L-1653
  - [Claude] Monet, Waterloo Bridge
    L-1654
  - Pablo Picasso Composition 1910 S. Guggenheim Collection
    L-1655
  - Unnamed castle
    L-1656
  - Nikolaus Pacassi, 'Lackzimmer' Schoenbrunn [Palace]
    L-1657